Tzivaras Vasileios

MSc in Computer Science & Engineering

Date of Birth: 24/07/1990 **Military Duty**: Served

vtzivaras@gmail.com
+30 6940361613
loannina, Greece
linkedin.com/in/vtzivaras
github.com/billytziv
vasilistzivaras.gr

Summary

Dynamic and motivated, with experience in networks, IoT and robotics, holding a MSc degree in Computer Science and Engineering. Team leadership and project management skills as former chairman of the IEEE University of Ioannina Student Branch. Enthusiastic about new technologies, authored two technical books about UAV and IoT. Fast learner, adaptive to new models and tools, able to carry out challenging and time demanding projects.

Soft Skills:	Project management		Leadership	Teamwork	Consistency	
Hard Skills:	OpenCV	Prototype boards	IoT networking protocols		Linux administration	Electronics

Education

04/07/2009 - 30/02/2018

MSc degree in Computer Science and Engineering

University of Ioannina, Ioannina, Greece (uoi.gr)

- o Integrated Master's Degree
- o Total ECTS: 300

Diploma thesis, University of Ioannina, Greece

Quadrotor landing using Visual Servoing

03/02/2016 - 01/01/2018

- o Quadcopter Physical/Simulation Modeling
- Image Based Visual Servoing (IBVS)

Work Experience

22/10/2018 - Present

Junior Software Developer

Omicron2, Greece

o Design and develop cross platform software in Adobe Animate CC

02/06/2015 - 08/12/2017

Technical Book Author / Reviewer

Packt Publishing, Birmingham, United Kingdom

- Author of "Building a Quadcopter with Arduino" technical book with ISBN 9781785281846
- Author of "Raspberry Pi Zero W Wireless Projects" technical book with ISBN 9781788290524
- Reviewer of "Internet of Things With Arduino Cookbook" with ISBN 9781785286582
- o Reviewer of "Building Smart Homes With Raspberry Pi Zero" with ISBN 9781786466952
- o Reviewer of "Intelligent IoT Projects in 7 Days" with ISBN

01/05/2011 - 04/03/2013

Volunteer: Computer and Network Technician

Computer Science and Engineering Dept, University of Ioannina, Greece

- Laboratory equipment maintenance
- o CSE department management assistant

01/05/2011 - 04/03/2013

Internship: Computer and Network Technician

Technical Dept, University hospital of Ioannina, Greece

- o Responsible for network maintenance and troubleshooting.
- Project coordinator

Volunteering

- o Former chairman of IEEE Student Branch at University of Ioannina
- o Member of Ioannina Linux User Group (ILUG)

Personal Skills

01/08/2009 - Present

Communication Skills

- Communication and collaboration skills gained through IEEE UOI SB leadership role and CSE department projects
- Presentation and leadership skills gained through IEEE UOI SB, FOSSCOMM conference and Ennovation competition
- Contact skills gained through my collaboration with PACKT Publishing, UK
- o Deadlines, consistency, leadership skills

01/08/2009 - Present

Organisational / Managerial Skills

- o Chairman of the IEEE Student Branch at University of Ioannina, Greece
- Responsible for software development at University Hospital of Ioannina, Greece
- o IoT team management through IEEE UOI Student Branch
- Leadership role in workshops and seminars through IEEE UOI Student Branch, FOSSCOM and Ennovation competition

Projects

Short list of the most proud projects

Project Title	Keywords			
Autonomous quadrotor landing	Robotics, Python, MATLAB, OpenCV, Kinematic and Dynamic			
using Visual Servoing	Model, Electronics, Arduino, Raspberry Pi			
Home Automation	Designed and developed a network working architecture using			
	Arduino and Raspberry Pi boards over Wifi and Ethernet			

Ticket Service Quick Recipient Designed and developed using PHP5, HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, MySQL A fast and quick way for ordering products which was, designed and Developed in Adobe Animate CC software